Emmet Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Oct 18, [1940] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: knitting for the troops; fears Bobby is campaigning for FDR
Oct 19, [1940] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia to paint blonde girl divorced from Russian prince; description of Willkie rally- Lydia dislikes song "God Bless America" Anne Hyde's wedding; Elizabeth Millet's wedding
Oct 24, [1940] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Uncle Ernest's home bombed--he died of shock, age 93; Jacquot and wife in Paris; Jane draws Mrs. Keilly; heard that Lamb House in Rye (Henry James' home) was destroyed; Roger in London; Zizi Rist and Charles
Nov 6, [1940] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Wilfrid has hernia; Posie's fall; Bob died; Jane and Lydia's exhibition--Cortissoz; FDR elected; Bay
Nov 8, 1940 - To: Mox Kobbe - From: Maria Kobbe - Subject: payment of $300 through State Dept.-- "maybe they will come over"
Nov 8, [1940] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: bombing in London--73 Cheyne Walk not hit, but will move furniture out
Nov 11, [1940] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: comments on the election; the Lunts
Nov 19, 1940 - To: Lydia - From: Annie [Wenlock] (in Bristol, England) - Subject: wartime situation
Nov 22, [1940] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Susie's stubborness; Jane tries to paint Guy
Nov 25, [1940] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia paints (Princess) Diana; wartime situation; Bobby and Madeleine back from Canada- McKenzie King
Nov 27, [1940] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Geoffrey Kerr's play
Dec 4, [1940] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Cynthia in hospital; Bill James and Bob; wartime situation--windows blown out of73 Cheyne Walk; will visit London for first time since the Blitz; will see Roger; Jane's foot trouble; the Lunts sent The White Cliffs to Jane
Dec 9, [1940?] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: the Lunts' play--Brooks Atkinson; Jane loves the "Golden Wedding" scene
Dec 10, [1940] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: saw Twelfth Night with Helen Hayes, Maurice Evans, and June Walker--benefit for Art Workers' Club; the Lunts; Elmer Rice's play
Dec 14, [1940] - To: Lydia - From: R. Keith Kane - Subject: thanks for portrait
Dec 1940 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: wartime situation; Bobby's writing
Dec 27, [1940] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Mark sings in the shelters; Bobby's Christmas visit; Ruth and Paul Draper's show
Dec 29, 1940 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: saw Twelfth Night; portrait orders from Stuyv. Pierrepont; Lydia to do pastel portrait of Caddy Taintor's grandchild; Dora's death
Jan 16, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bill took Nelly Hall to hear Lily Pons; Bobby's gold medal from Institute of Arts and Letters; Harpo Marx; Mrs. Miller's White Cliffs;Willkie's activities; Joseph Kennedy; Douglas Fairbanks, Jr.
Jan 18, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: finished portrait; Willkie; the election; Alice D. Miller; Alexander Woollcott; Cynthia is ill
Jan 19, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: looked at dreary 73 Cheyne Walk; Phil in motor accident; Lunts; FDR inauguration; Willkie's visit
Jan 26, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane has carbuncle; "thing" on Lydia's face; The White Cliffs; Lunts; Phil Marsh engaged to Mary Hewetson
Jan 29, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Dooly works in "Bundles for Britain" warehouse; Madeleine at Arizona ranch; the inauguration--Madeleine, the Masseys, Elmer Rice; Behrman's play--Phil Merivale
Jan 30,1941 - To: Jane - From: Roger Quilter - Subject: The White Cliffs; wartime situation
Feb 7, 1941 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby in Arizona--William Allen White visited him; the Lunts
Feb 14, [1941] - To: Ros - From: Jane - Subjects: carbuncle is gone; Royal Academy show; Geoffrey Kerr's play
Feb 14, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: Maria Schaefer - Subjects: the loan of a book; Lydia's health
Mar 3, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bob and Madeleine visited the Lunts in Los Angeles; Bob wants to talk to Harry Hopkins; Lydia's portrait of Diana was refused by the Corcoran
Mar 7, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: concern over Jane's carbuncles; story of Mrs. Weston's great-grandfather Elisha Boudinot speaking with George Washington when Boudinot's little daughter came in and Washington said "don't go you little yellow bird" and picked her up; Kitty Denbigh wants Bobby to work for Franco; John and Charlotte Rand have a daughter
Mar 7, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Susie got money from America; Loulou's uncle General Delacroix
Mar 15, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Roger Quilter - Subject: Bobby Sherwood is a hero
Mar 20, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby speech-writing for FDR; Willkie and Churchill; Ros met Somerset Maugham at Lady Cunard's party
Mar 22, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: wartime situation; Roger admires Bobby
Mar 27, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane's improving health world events
Mar 29, 1941 - To: Annie - From: Geraldine Millet - Subject: description of travels
Mar 29, 1941 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: DeLauncy Jay's death
Mar 30, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Tempy visit--Lydia took him to the Frick
Apr 2, 1941 - To: ? - From: ? (carbon copy) - Subject: description of conditions in France
Apr 14, 1941 - To: Conde Nast - From: Frank Crowninshield - Subjects: statement of his opinion of Lindbergh (with added comment by Lydia)
Apr 14, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby's speech-writing; Bob had the flu; relations of the Hepburns and the Emmets
Apr 17, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: 73 Cheyne Walk destroyed; Emily Sargent; Lydia painted a boy
[Apr 22, 1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: There Shall Be No Night has been well received; the Lunts in Wisconsin; Maurice Colbourne
Apr 23, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Le Braz's only son killed in the last war, his son-in-law May help Susie; destruction of 73 Cheyne Walk; Wilfrid to go to varnishing at Royal Academy; Roger
Apr 29, [1941] - To: Posie - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane did drawing of Bob Brand for Phyllis and Wilfrid painted her
Apr 29, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: sorrow over 73 Cheyne Walk; Bobby's speech-writing
May 1, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Walter Lippmann likes Bobby's play; Edna Ferber; Noel Coward; McKenzie King, P.M. of Canada; the Lunts; Bay; John and Charlotte wedding
May 5, 1941 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bobby won Pulitzer Prize
May 7, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: Willkie; Bobby Sherwood; White Cliffs
May 8, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby won Pulitzer Prize for There Shall Be No Night; the Lunts; Bobby dined with Polly Howard who said another (unidentified) invitee refused to dine with Bobby; Bobby distressed at the destruction of Old Chelsea Church which had contained plaques to Henry James and to Jane Colt (wife of Thomas More); Bobby avoiding Lady Cunard
Jun 2, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Aunt Bella's death; Bobby's honorary Yale degree; little Mary graduated college
Jun 4, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: FDR's speech--Lydia's bad opinion of FDR
Jun 9, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Lydia Sherwood Williams - Subjects: asks Lydia not to distress Jane and Wilfrid by criticizing FDR
Jun 18, [1941] - To: PosieFrom:Alice Duer Miller - Subjects: autograph tour with White Cliffs
Jun 30, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Helen says Bill had a heart attack
Jul 1, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: H.L.R. Emmet - Subject: Uncle Bill is doing well
Jul 10, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Roger; Loulou's mother, Genevieve Micheli; Susie sees Jacquot; Russian war; thanks for food
Jul 17, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: news of French friends and family; Walter Lipmann and D.T. (Dorothy Thompson?) are grand; one of Robert Emmet's grandsons killed in train accident; Delauncy Jay's death--he was good to Lybba
Jul 18, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Posie admired Tolstoy; Bobby is assistant to "Wild Bill" Donovan, Coordinator of Defense Intelligence; Wodehouse; Cynthia in hospital
Jul 26, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: war situation
Jul 28, [1941] - To: Nite - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid is a Home Guard Quarter Master; he had an order for a portrait; will visit Guy Rawlence
Jul 31, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Susie's finances; demolition of 73 Cheyne Walk; Picasso; Pablo
Aug 7, 1941 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: music festival; Lydia will allow long-term renters to make changes to Strawberry Hill; Posie fell
Aug 19, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Geraldine Millet - Subject: loved singing songs during her visit
Aug 20, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Marga to be married to Jack
Aug 22, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: Polly Howard - Subject: interested in contacting the spiritual world (includes Lydia's note describing her medium's contact with Sidney Howard)
Aug 27, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: description of Marga's wedding to Jack Chapman?
Sep 22, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: Nite - Subject: milk business
Sep 26, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Bill Emmet died today--he'll be buried in Arlington Cemetery
Oct 9, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bill's death and will; sore on Lydia's neck
Oct 12, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Geraldine Millet - Subject: her activities
Oct 15, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Wilfrid begins portrait; Bill's death; Alexander Woollcott
Oct 25, 1941 - To: Ros - From: Roger Quilter - Subject: Bill's death
Oct 25, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subject: Bill's death
Oct 26, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: R. Keith Kane(Department of Justice) - Subject: shipment of portrait
Oct 31, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Lydia in hospital; Bill's funeral; Hermie engaged; Phil's wife Mary
Nov 25, 1941 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: repair of a Rosina Hubley painting; death of Maggie's only grandson
Nov 27, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Ginny Sherwood to work for Archibald MacLeish at Library of Congress; Lydia's invitation to Cos Cob Club from Clare Boothe Luce; Dooly's job designing mannequins
Dec 9, 1941 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: Jane and Wilfrid move on Jan 6
Dec 11, [1941] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: reaction to Pearl Harbor; Jane's drawing of Norman for Elma
Dec 11, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor; Lindbergh; Hamilton Fish; Bay does portraits for British War Relief; wedding of Hermie and "girl with a past"
Dec 20, [1941] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bay's death from heart disease and complications; Blanchard's character; Bay's funeral in Salisbury; baby named Ellen Emmet Rand; construction on Strawberry Hill going well; Cynthia to have kidney operation
Jan 1, 1942 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Hermie's wedding; Bob and Madeleine at Harrimans' party with Irving Berlin; Dooly's job; Cynthia's operation went well; Hope Noyes' death
Jan 15, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Mary Sherwood likes Lydia's painting ofNelly Hall; Bobby's work in DC
Jan 16, 1942 - To: Lydia - From: Dana - Subject: thanks for portrait of Bill
Jan 18, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Anne to marry Gloster Beveridge Aaron; Hope Noyes' death in plane crash; Lydia works on the Allen portrait; "Old Rosina's" death; Kitty Keogh had stroke
Jan 24, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bay's funeral; "Old Rosina's" death; Madeleine's grandchild named after Cynthia; Susie and Pablo; Allen portrait by Lydia
Jan 25, [1942] - To: Hetty - From: Lydia - Subjects: Nite's milk business; Beulah's baby R.T.E.; Robin's portrait by Lydia; Jane moved to Manor Farm on Jan 6
Feb 9, 1942 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Leslie is still in Bay's apartment; Susie and Pablo; seances
Feb 10, 1942 - To: Lydia - From: Marie Kobbe - Subjects: heard that P. (Pablo) had been released from concentration camp and is now in Paris
Feb 23, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: "Old Rosina's" death; Lydia's painting of Sabette Allen; Eisenberg has a nice face; Bev and Anne's wedding; Lilli Kobbe
Mar 4, 1942 - To: Lydia - From: ? - Subjects: understands why Susie went to Europe; American mail to Pablo
May be an embarrassment
Mar 5, [1942] - To: Wilfrid - From: Posie - Subjects: descriptions of Bobby's meetings with Churchill and FDR; Madeleine goes to business school-- Ruth Gordon phoned to see how it went
Mar 9, 1942 - To: Lydia - From: Geraldine Millet - Subject: her activities
Mar 16, 1942 - To: Lydia - From: Julian [Allen] - Subject: thanks for Sabette's portrait
Mar 21, [1942] - To: Lydia - From: Jane (Manor Farm, Stratford Tony, Salisbury) - Subjects: Eisenberg's face; Jane's portrait of Francis, Gen. Casement's son; Jane's portraits of Mrs. Hill and Mrs. Radcliff; Jane dislikes Lydia's opinion of FDR; description of new home; (drawings of porch and floor plan)
[Mar 1942] - To: Dear ones - From: Wilfrid - Subject: Bobby's visit to England
Mar 25, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Phil's ulcer operation; Bobby's work in DC; Posie's opinion of MacArthur
Apr 3, 1942 - To: Posie - From: Phil - Subjects: his operation; Philby
Apr 10, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Jim Townsend Jr. will join the RAF
Apr 13, [1942] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: news of Susie and Louis
Apr 30, [1942] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: rationing; works look good at Royal Academy
May 3, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Eleanor's son Howdy Lapsley killed in plane accident; (photograph of Ros, Jerry, and Heidi)
May 4, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Howdy Lapsley's death; Susie--Louis' "automatic" powers
May 17, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: copy of Bobby's Mother's Day poem
May 25, [1942] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Susie and Louis will not leave Paris until "voices" tell them to
Jun 6, [1942] - To: Posie - From: Jane - Subjects: life at Manor Farm; Jane's drawings of Lord Herbert's children
Jun 23, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Susie's finances; Lydia's left arm swollen; Lydia May paint Mrs. Rockwood; Phil's operation
Jul 6, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lydia talks too fast; Lydia and Posie have trouble walking
Jul 14, [1942] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Barbara Lister expecting; Ruth Draper; Dickey and Helen divorce; Lily Cushing having affair with Henri Bernstein; (8 photographs of Manor Farm House, Jane, Wilfrid, and Roger Quilter)
Aug 28, 1942 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: invited the Queen and little Dutch princesses to play with our children
Sep 15, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Pacific war; Bob and Madeleine not going to live in DC; Monty Woolley's movie Pied Piper
Sep 29, 1942 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Lydia moved Elsie Colt into nursing home; Nelly Hall and Ham Smith's wedding; Ellen Biddle divorced
Oct 13, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Dooly training for radiocode transmission; Le Havre bombed
Oct 15, [1942] - To: Lydia - From: Betsy - Subjects: Jim in flight training--visit with Barry Jones and Maurice Colburne
Oct 22, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Posie fell; old pastel of John Colt; Jim Townsend Jr. killed Oct 24
Nov 8, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Jim's death--no reaction from Cynthia; Arch is a captain; E. Biddle has had a heart attack and blindness in past
Nov 24, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bobby's observations of the Roosevelts; wartime situation
Nov 25, 1942 - To: Jane - From: Barry Jones - Subjects: Jim's death; Jones' attempt at painting
Nov 28, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby's wartime activities-- he admires Eisenhower
Dec 3, 1942 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: he enjoyed his visit with Jane; saw play The Man Who Came to Dinner
Dec 6, 1942 - To: Lydia - From: Harry Leith-Ross - Subject: thanks for information about Philby portrait
Dec 6, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: family members in the war; Averell Harriman had to leave for Russia before having a steak; the Lunts
Dec 19, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Posie's fall--broken pelvis
Dec 30, [1942] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Bobby writing an FDR biography
Jan 6, 1943 - To: Friends - From: Jane - Subjects: Jim's death; Ginny; Roger; Barry Jones and Maurice Colbourne; saw The Man Who Came to Dinner
Feb 17, 1943 - To: Lydia - From: Nite - Subject: thanks for Nell's portrait
Mar 13, [1943] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Bobby to visit; wartime situation
Mar 29, [1943] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Cynthia's death; Lynn Fontanne; Geoffrey Kerr; Coward's Blithe Spirit
Apr 10, 1943 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Cynthia's funeral; Ros' job; Bob will adapt There Shall Be No Night for the Lunts in London
Apr 17, 1943 - To: Jim, Dooly, and Betsy - From: Lydia Emmet Williams (in North Africa) - Subject: Cynthia's death; her war work; Dooly's application for war work
May 19, 1943 - To: Evie Sherwood - From: Lydia Emmet Williams (in North Africa) - Subject: her war work
Jun 5, 1943 - To: W.L.R. Emmet - From: Helen Landreth - Subject: research on Robert Emmet
Jun 22, 1943 - To: Posie - From: Madeleine Sherwood - Subjects: her travels from DC to NY; the Lunts; Bobby's work
Aug 5, 1943 - To: Posie - From: Madeleine Sherwood - Subjects: Bobby's work; Mary wants to be an actress
Aug 30 1943 - To: Posie - From: Madeleine - Subjects: Bobby and Madeleine to go to a dinner for Brendan Bracken; Mary will return to Bennington College; Ruth Gordon and Garson Kanin live at Willard Hotel; Geoffrey Kerr to marry Margot Kling
Oct 3, 1943 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Lydia locked in her bathroom
Nov 23, 1943 - To: Lydia - From: Helen Landreth - Subject: research on Robert Emmet
Dec 25, 1943 - To: ? - From: The Sherwoods - Subject: Christmas card designed by R.E.S. II
Jan 1, 1944 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Elizabeth's death
Jan 1, 1944 - To: Arthur and Ev - From: Ginny - Subjects: Arch to marry Dizzy; Christmas with Jane
May 12, 1944 - To: Lydia - From: Mabel Bowring - Subject: loves the portrait
Jun 11, 1944 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Jane's activities described in a letter from the Lunts; Bobby dislikes Jerry
Jul 8, 1944 - To: Papa and Batsy - From: Dooly - Subjects: tea with Maurice Colbourne--Barry Jones was away; D-Day; Betty Hitchcock; Bobby in England; Roger Quilter
Aug 7, 1944 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Philby's death
Sep 14, 1944 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Mary Sherwood is engaged
Dec 31, [1944] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Elma's son born; Wilfrid painted daughter of Mrs. Legh last spring; the Lunts
Jan 1, 1945 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: book about Henry James by Matthieson; Eddie Morgan's visit--he fought in the Pacific
Jan 21, [1945] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Jane did portrait of John Page Phillips
Feb 20, [1945?] - To: Posie - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid paints Michael Astor, M.P.; Spencer Tracy walked out of play (Rugged Path?)
Feb 21, [1945] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Lydia likes Mary's fiance; Richard Collison and Jean married only a few months; Roger better; O'Neill plays; Thornton Wilder plays
Feb 26, [1945] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (214 E 70th) - Subjects: Red Cross portrait; Geraldine Millet died Saturday; Yalta
[1945] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bob met MacArthur; Arch received Croix de Guerre; Ros and Dozia met Edna Ferber
Apr 5, [1945] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Red Cross portrait; painter Margaret Hawley
Apr 17, 1945 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Susie's news; FDR's death
May 2, [1945] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid at Royal Academy varnishing day; the Lunts; German death camps
May 11, [1945] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Ray Massey read Bobby's eulogy for FDR; Pablo in seclusion in France--Susie may not return
May 14, [1945] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: opera singer Charlotte Ryan related to Mrs. Legh
May 20, [1945] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia paints little Beulah as wedding gift; Strawberry Hill rented to Justine Bayard Cutting, sister of Henry James' ex-wife who lives in Tyringham; Ruth Draper entertaining troops
May 29, [1945] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: book about Henry James; Minnie Temple had been courted by Oliver Wendell Holmes; Bobby writing a new play
Dec 12, 1945 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subject: Christmas greetings
Dec 21, [1945] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Evie will deliver Jane's painting of a rose to Susie; Winty wants Jane to paint a portrait of Evie
Mar 31, [1946] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: new Steinway piano selected by pianist Kathleen Long; Wilfrid did portrait of Louis
May 13, [1946] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid to paint Barbara Astor; Jane to exhibit 30 year old portrait of Lynn Fontanne
May 23, 1946 - To: Robert Sherwood - From: Harry S. Truman(transcript of letter) - Subject: offer of assistance on Harry L. Hopkins book
May 25, 1946 - To: Lydia - From: John A. Campbell Vanderpoel Art Assn. - Subject: Lydia's "The Girl in Pink" is stealing the show
Jun 20, 1946 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Susie; Jacquot goes to South America
Jul 12, [1946] - To: Ros - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane visited with Bobby, Madeleine, the Averell Harrimans, and Winston Churchill, Jr.; description of garden party at Buckingham Palace; Jane visited Ruth Draper, Violet and Francis Ormond
Sep 4, [1946] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane paints surgeon's daughter and Michael Harrison's son; Susie's recordings
Sep 16, [1946] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Elma's son John
Oct 4, [1946] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Zena's wedding; Susie and "poor old Louis"
Nov 17, [1946] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Tommy visits before return to US; Ruth Draper visit; Jane to paint daughters of Lady Lucas and Col. Cooper
Nov 19, [1946] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: few read Henry James now
Feb 7, [1947] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Wilfrid paints Scottish widow and Mrs. Menzies
Mar 26, [1947] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Kitty's funeral; death of Loulou Emmet; Wilfrid painting Mrs. Lindsay (Bay painted her sister)
Apr 18, [1947] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: visit to Elma's; Jane's neighbor Bruce Richmond was a Times editor; Jane to paint Belinda
Apr 23, 1947 - To: Lydia - From: ? - Subject: (typed statement on the death of Eliza Wedgwood)
May 4, 1947 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: death of Mox Kobbe; Mary's wedding pictures
May 21, 1947 - To: Jane - From: Percy Grainger - Subject: family news
Jun 11, [1947] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: hairnets; Barry Jones; Percy Grainger; Lydia to paint Mary
Jun 30, 1947 - To: Lydia - From: Mary Sherwood - Subject: Mary and Bud
Jul 12, 1947 - To: Lydia - From: Jane (in Cannes) - Subjects: saw Susie; description of France after war
Aug 18,1947 - To: Jane - From: Susie - Subject: her stay in Villefranche
Sep 4, 1947 - To: Lydia - From: George L. Stout Worcester Art Museum - Subject: possible acquisition of Lydia's portrait of Susie
Sep 13, [1947] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: clearing "chaos" from her studio and apartment; young Eddie works on the Herald Tribune and is dating Gertrude Vanderbilt's granddaughter; Helen Landreth's book
Oct 29, [1947] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Winant has cancer
Nov 7, [1947] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Winant's death; Jane's portrait of Michael Clark's daughter Jocelyn; Wilfrid painted a man from Norwich